# Mustafa Akbari Software Engineer

Email: Akbarimustafa64@gmail.com Phone: 00491795253045

Phone: 0049179525304 Birth date: 06.12.1991

Address: Am Steinfeld 3, 85659 Forstern, Germany

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mustafa-akbari-289543219/

GitHub: https://github.com/ci-mustafa

# **Executive Summary**

Experienced IT professional with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and over 5 years in IT administration, database management, and web development. Proven ability to solve problems and communicate effectively. Currently advancing skills through a Full Stack Development program at Code Institute. Seeking to contribute to and grow within a development team.

# **Technical Skillset**

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Containers	APIs	Operating sys	VC sys
Python JavaScript CSS3, HTML5	MySQL Postgres	Django, jQuery Bootstrap, Flask Jest, Pytest	Docker	Restfull API	Windows Linux	Git Github

## **Work Experience**

November 2022- January 2024

### Freelancer (Backend Development)

Spottech, New Zealand

- Development and implementation of backend functions for various applications.
- Integrated API endpoints and developed database-driven functions using Django.
- Consistently optimize and maintain applications to uphold high standards of performance and quality.
- Effectively improved and optimized SQL databases, resulting in a 30% improvement in query performance and ensuring high availability to meet end-user requirements for over 1,000 users.

March 2017–October 2020

#### **Database Administrator**

UHCC, Afg

- Designed and created databases using MySQL, and integrated with third-party applications via MySQL Workbench.
- Maintained database standards and policies, achieving 99.9% uptime.
- Managed database availability and performance.
- Implemented event triggers for problem detection.
- Performed database maintenance and optimization, improving performance by 55%.
- Monitor usage and security.

February 2015–January 2017

#### IT Administrator

TMB, Afg

- Troubleshot network issues, reducing downtime by 20%.
- Managed and maintained printers, copiers, and fax machines for 100+ users.
- Conducted server maintenance and implemented disaster recovery plans, achieving 99.9% data availability.
- Monitored UPS workstations and operational printers.
- Provided backup support for workflow systems.
- Ensured password and data security in desktop environments.

## **Education**

February 2024–Present Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

December 2020-August 2022 Skills Enhancement Udemy, Code with Mosh (online resources)

November 2010—December 2014 Bachelor of Computer Science Aria University

# **Certifications**

Bachelor of Computer Science
Code Institute - Fullstack Web Development – on going
Code with Mosh – Complate Django (16 hours)
Udemy – 100 Days of Code (54 hours)
Python Programming Masterclass (63 hours)

# Language Skills

Good German Fluent English Fluent Turkish Native Persion

